Guide to the Larry Spruch Papers MC.209
New York University Archives
- Series II: Correspondence, 1941-2005
  - Jim, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, undated (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Len [?], undated (Box 12, Folder 50)
- Series III: China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application (CUSPEA) Program, 1980-1987
  Series III contains materials from Larry Spruch's participation in the China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application (CUSPEA) program in the 1980s. Drafts and final copies of exams in English and Physics which Spruch helped to develop are included, as are Spruch's correspondence with other CUSPEA-affiliated physicists and the administrators of the program. A diary and ephemera from Spruch's 1985 trip to China, which was taken under the auspices of the program to interview prospective graduate students, are also included in this series.
  - Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Record booklet, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Participating Universities, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Larry Spruch's China travel journal, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - China travel ephemera, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - CUSPEA English proficiency test, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - CUSPEA exam notes, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Record booklet, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Publication List of the Members of China Center of Advanced Science and Technology - World Laboratory, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Record booklet, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Exam forms, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Classical Physics exam, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Classical Physics exam and notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Possible exam problems, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Notes for China visit, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Larry Spruch's China travel journal (another), undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Professional Materials, 1927-2004; 1950-2002
  Series IV encompasses various aspects of Larry Spruch's participation in the international community of physics scholars. The series is divided into four subseries.
  Subseries A: Manuscript and Research Proposal Referrals contains Spruch's reviews of manuscripts submitted by other physicists for publication in various academic journals, as well as reviews of a handful of research proposals. These materials are not open to researchers.
  Subseries B: Works by Other Physicists contains published articles and manuscripts to which Spruch did not personally contribute, but in which he seems to have taken a professional interest. Nearly all of these materials are heavily annotated by Spruch, and many are also accompanied by his own calculations of problems discussed in the texts, or his correspondence with the authors. The arrangement system of this subseries is somewhat complex because it maintains some aspects of the collection's original order. For example, while Spruch seems to have generally grouped materials of this type together by author and arranged the folders in alphabetical order by the author's last name, some materials were also grouped topically or by the publication in which they appeared. The materials in this subseries date from between 1927 and 2004, though the bulk of them date from between 1950 and 2002.
  Subseries C: Conferences, Workshops, and Seminars contains materials from professional gatherings, many of them international, in which Spruch participated or simply attended. These materials include notes on presentations given by Spruch or other physicists, event programs, correspondence with event organizers and participants, and documentation of Spruch's travel to and from the events. Especially well-represented in this series are materials from the Aspen Center for Physics, a summer research program in Aspen, Colorado in which Spruch participated frequently. The materials in this subseries date from between 1956 and 2003.
  Subseries D: Awards and Honors contains materials related to some—though not all—of the numerous awards and honors which Larry Spruch received throughout his career. Many of the materials included in the series are related to a website created by the NYU Physics department in 2000 in honor of Larry Spruch. Spruch's Brooklyn College Alumni Award of Honor in this subseries dates from 1967, though the other materials date from the latter part of his career, between 1984 and 2001.
  - Subseries B: Works by Other Physicists, 1927-2004; 1950-2002
    - Abdel-Raouf, M. A., 1978-1984 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ajaya [probably Mohanty], "Bremsstrahlung and Threshold Laws for the Electron" manuscript, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Akerib, Richard and Sidney Borowitz, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Akhieser, A. I. and V. B. Berestetsky, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Amundsen, P. A., D. H. Jakubaßa-Amundsen, and M. Kleber, 1980-1985 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Armour, E.A.G., 1977 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Armour, E.A.G., 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Aronowitz, Stanley, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Aspect, A., 1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Aspect, Alain and Jean Dalibard, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Au, C. K., 1984 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Au, C. K., 1984-1987 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Auvil, P.R., 1968, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Avron, J. E. and I. W. Herbst, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Babb, James F., 1998 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Bahcall, John N., 1977-1992 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Balian, R. and C. Bloch, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Balian, Roger and Bertrand Duplantier, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Barbieri, R., 1970 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Barton, G., 1970-1990 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Barton, G., 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Barton, G., 2000 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Baumol, William J., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Baym, Gordon and Christopher Pethick, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Baym, Gordon and Christopher Pethick, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Bazley, Norman W., 1959 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Bazley, Norman W., 1960-1965 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Bell, John S., 1964-1966 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Bender, Carl M., L.D. Mlodinow, and N. Papanicolaou, undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Berestetskii, V. B., undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Bethe, H. A., S. P. Rosen, and J. M. Gelb, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Bhaduri, R. K., Y. Nogami, and C. S. Warke, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Blau, Robert, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Blau, Robert, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Blokhintsev, L. D., 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Bludman, S., 2003 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Boehm, George A. W., 1960 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Bohr, Niels and Aage Bohr, 1948-1954 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Bordag, M., 1992 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Born, M., undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Borowitz, Sidney and Edward Gerjuoy, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Boulware, David G. and S. Deser, 1975, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Boyer, Timothy H., 1968-1984 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Brandt, Richard, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Brandt, Richard A., 2004 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Bressi, G., G. Carugno, R. Onofrio, and G. Ruoso, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Bressi, G., G. Carugno, R. Onofrio, G. Ruoso, and F. Veronese, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Briand, Jean-Pierre; William Clark and Chris H. Greene; R. Ingersoll and D. H. Liebenberg; A. Dalgarno and A. E. Kingston, 1956, 1995-1999 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Briggs, J. S., 1976-1991 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Brown, Lowell S., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Brush, Stephen J., undated (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Bryce, W. M. and F. Mandl; Edward Gerjuoy, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Burgess, A., 1959-1970 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Burke, P. G., 1963, 1980-1982 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Calogero, F., 1964-1972, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Campeanu, R. I. and J. W. Humberston, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - Candelas, P., 1982, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - Canuto, V., 1972-1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Carraro, Carlo and Milton W. Cole, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cavagnero, Michael, 1992-1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Chan, H. B., V. A. Aksyuk, D. J. Bishop, and Federico Capasso, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Chang, Edward S., undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Chang, R. K. and T. E. Furtak, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Chen, Joseph, 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Chen, Zonghua, 1991-1994, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Cheon, Il-Tong, 1988-1997 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Chernikov, Alexander, A., Roald Z. Sagdeev, and George M. Zaslavsky, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Chou, Chih-Kang, 1969-1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Clark, C. W. and K. T. Taylor, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Cohen, Jeffrey M., undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Cohen-Tannoudji, C., 1976-1984 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Constantinescu, Dan H. and Pavel Rehák, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Cornille, H. and A. Martin, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Crisp, Michael D., 1990 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Curtis, L. J., 1981 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Dalgarno, A., 1961-1977, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Dalgarno, A. and J. F. Babb, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Damburg, R. J., 1968 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - de Llano, Manuel, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Deloff, A., 1963 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Delves, L. M., 1963 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Demkov, Yuri, 1958-2001 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Dettman, K., K. G. Harrison, and M. W. Lucas, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Dittruch, W. and M. Reuter, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Drachman, Richard, 1963-1966 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Drachman, Richard J., 1982, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Drake, G. F. W., 1990-1993 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Dvali, G. and John C. Price, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - DeRaad, Lester L. Jr. and Julian Schwinger, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Dyson, F. J., 1952 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Dyson, Freeman J., 1967-1980 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Efimov, Vitaly, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Einstein, A., translated by Charles Jaffé, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Eisenbud, L. and E. P. Wigner, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Eissner, W. and H. Nussbaumer, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Elizade, E., 1988 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Englert, Berthold-Georg and Julian Schwinger, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Essex, Christopher, Dallas C. Kennedy, and Sidney A. Bludman, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Faddeyev, L. D., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Faddeyev, L. D., and Leonard Rosenberg, 1961-1968 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Falk, H. and M. H. Mittleman, 1965-1970 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - Faris, William G., 1974 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Fefferman, Charles L., 1983 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Feinberg, G., 1970-1986 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Feshbach, Herman, 1958-1962 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Foster, Brian, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Frank, Winfried and Peter von Brentano, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Friedman, B. and E. Gerjuoy, undated (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - Friedrichs, K. O., 1955 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - French, A., undated (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Fushiki, I., undated (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Gadiyak, G. V. and Yu E. Lozovik, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Gallagher, T. F. and W. E. Cooke, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Gallas, Jason A. C., 1984 (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - Gay, J. C., 1981-1985 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Garstang, R. H., 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - Gerjuoy, Edward, 1953-1997 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Gerjuoy, Edward: Testimony Presented to the Joint Hearings: Investigations and Oversight Subcommittee and Science, Research and Technology Subcommittee of the House Committee on Science and Technology, on the Impact of National Security Concerns on Science and Technology, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Gerjuoy, Edward, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Giese, Clayton F. and W. Ronald Gentry, 1993, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - Glasser, M. L., 1971-1975 (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Glassgold, A. E., 1964 (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Glassgold, A. E. and William D. Langer, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - Goldberger, Marvin L.: notes on J. Schwinger's quantum theory of fields, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Goldman, S. P., 1986-1998 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Goldstein, Herbert, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Good, R. H., undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Gray, C. G., G. Karl, and V. A. Novikov, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Greenblatt, M. H., 1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Greene, Chris, 1985-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Greene, Chris H. and Richard J. Drachman, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Griffith, T. C. and G. R. Heyland, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Guth, Alan H. and Paul J. Steinhardt, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Hagedorn, R., 1971 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Hahn, Yukap, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Hahn, Yukap, 1965-1976 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Haines, Larry K. and David H. Roberts, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Hamada, T. and E. E. Salpeter, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Hamilton, J., I. Øverbö, and B. Tromberg, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Hartle, J. B., 1977 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Hawton, Margaret, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Hegstrom, Roger A., 1982 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Herschbach, Dudley, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Herschbach, Dudley R., undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Heydenburg, N. P. and G. M. Temmer, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Hill, Robert Nyden, 1976-1994 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Hills, J. G., Myron Lecar, 1975-1977 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Hinds, E. A., 1991-1994 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Hogreve, H., 1992 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Holcomb, Robert W., 1970 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Holstein, T., 1965 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Hughes, Vernon, 1980-1982 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Hushwater, V., 1997 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Hut, Piet, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Inokuti, Mitio, 1967-1978 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Iwinski, Z. R., 1980 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Jhe, W. and J. W. Kim, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Jura, M. and A. Dalgarno, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Kadomtsev, B. B., 1970 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Kadomtsev, B. B. and V. S. Kudryavtsev, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Kalikstein, K., 1964-1981 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Kanada, H., J. L. Osborne, and L. Schlessinger, 1966, 1968, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Kanada, H. and B. T. Kim, 1980-1982 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Kanada, H., Y. C. Tang, and B. W. Filippone, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Kay, Irvin, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Kay, Irvin, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Kay, I. and H. E. Moses, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Keller, Joseph B., 1956 (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Keller, Joseph B., 1957-1990 (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Kennedy, Dallas C., Sidney A. Bludman, and H. Nakano, 1963, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Kleinman, Chemia and Leonard Rosenberg, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Kleppner, Dan, 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Kobach, Ladislav, 1976-1982 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Kohn, Walter, 1947-1954 (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Kräwinkel, H. and A. C. Allison, 1971, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Kupiszewska, Dorota, 1990-1993 (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Kylafis, Nikolaos D., 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Labzowsky, L. N., 1973 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Lamoreaux, S. K., 1999 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Langer, Steven H., 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Larsen, David M., undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Lassettre, Edwin N., 1965-1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Lassettre, Edwin, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Le Dorneuf, M., 1977-1982 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Le Guillou, J. C. and J. Zinn-Justin, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Lenard, A. and Freeman J. Dyson, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Levin, F., 1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Levy-Leblond, Jean-Marc, 1963-1976 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Levy-Leblond, Jean-Marc, 1966-1969 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Levy-Leblond, Jean-Marc, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1976, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1977 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1978-1984 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Lieb, Elliot H. and Barry Simon, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1981 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1983-1988 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Lieb, Elliot H. and Walter Thirring, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1989 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Lieb, Elliot H., 1992-1995 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Lieber, M., 1978-1982 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Lifshitz, E. M., 1956-1961 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Lippman, B. A., 1949-1968 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Livingston, A. Eugene, 1985-1995 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Lozovik, Yu. E., 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Lu, K. T., F. S. Tomkins, H. M. Crosswhite and H. Crosswhite, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Luehr, Charles P., 1962 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Lütken, C. A. and F. Ravndal, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Maia Neto, P. A., 1993 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Maleki, Nasser, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - March, N. H., 1957 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - March, N. H. and Y. Tomishima, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - March, N. H. and R. F. W. Bader, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Martin, André, 1957-1991 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Marxer, Hermann, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - McCarroll, R., 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - McElroy, Michael B. and Joseph O. Hirschfelder, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Miller, William H., 1995 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Mills, Robert, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Milonni, P. W., 1981 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - Milonni, P. W., 1982-1993 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Milonni, Peter W., 1982-1994 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - Milonni, P. W., 1988-1993 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - Milonni, P. W., 1995, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - Milonni, Peter W., undated (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - Milton, K. A., 1980 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - Mittleman, Marvin H., 1975 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Mohanty, Ajaya K., 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - Mohideen, U. and Anushee Roy, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - Mohr, Peter J. and Barry N. Taylor, Robert A. Nelson, 1999-2001 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - Moore, Steven, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Morgan, John D. III, 1983-1993 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - Moses, H. E., 1951 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - Moses, Harry E., 1953 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - Murnick, D. E., 1987-1990 (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - Narnhofer, H. and W. Thirring, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Neuhauser, D., 1987 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Neumann, R., 1994 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Nicolaides, C. A., 1978-1984 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Norcross, David, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Norcross, David W., 1977 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Novak, Edward, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Nowak, E., J. Sucher, and C. H. Woo, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Nuttall, J., 1979 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Nussenzveig, H. M., 1962 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Nussenzveig, H. M., 1962 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - O'Malley, Thomas F., 1964-1968 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Onda, Kunizo, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Orear, Jay and E. E. Salpeter, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Osborne, John Lawrence, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Patil, S. H., 1982 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Pechukas, Philip, 1966-1972 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Peek, James M. and Jacob Katriel, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Percival, I. C., 1973 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Percus, J. K., 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Pfeifer, Peter, 1993-1995 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Pines, David, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Plunien, Günter, Berndt Müller, and Walter Greiner, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Power, E. A., 1969-1978, 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Power, Edwin A., 1972, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Power, Edwin A., 1973-1977 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Puthoff, H. E., 1987-1994, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Rau, A. R. P., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Rau, A. R. P., 1971-1982 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Rau, A. R. P., 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Rau, A. R. P., 1978 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Rau, A. R. P., 1984-1992 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Rau, A. R. P., undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Reinhardt, William P., 1972-1982 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Renne, M. J., 1971 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Robertson, R. G. H. et al.; G. R. Plattner, M. P. Bornand, R. D. Viollier, and K. Alder, 1976-1983 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Robertson, R. G. H., P.l Dyer, R. A. Warner, R. C. Melin, T. J. Bowles, A. B. McDonald, G. C. Ball, W. G. Davies, and E. D. Earle, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Robinson, E. J., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Robinson, E. J., 1980 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Robinson, E. J., 1984-1990 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Robinson, E. J., 1986 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Rohrlich, Fritz, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Rosen, Bernard, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, 1972-1993 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Rosenberg, Leonard, undated (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Rotenberg, Manuel, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Ruderman, Malvin, 1965-1979 (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - Ruderman, M., 1974-1976 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - Ruderman, M., 1994 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - Rueda, A., 1984 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Sadeghpour, H. R., 2000 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Saito, S., R. Tamagaki, and O. Endō, 1964-1973 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Salpeter, E. E., 1960-1989 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Salpeter, E. E., 1973 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Sattler, K., J. Mühlbach, O. Echt, P. Pfau, and E. Recknagel, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Schaden, Martin, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Schaden, Martin, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Schaden, Martin, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Schaden, Martin, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Schaden, Martin, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Schiff, L. I., 1946 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Schmiedmeyer, Jörg, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Schram, K., 1975 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Schuch, R., 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Schüßler, T. V. Schramm, T. Rüter, C. Broude, M. Grieser, D. Habs, D. Schwalm, and A. Wolf, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Schwartz, Charles, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Schwebel, Solomon L., 1954 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Schwinger, Julian, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Schwinger, Julian, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Schwinger, Julian, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Seaton, M. J., 1953-1966 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Seaton, M. J. and Lois Steenman-Clark, undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Serber, R., 1976 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Shakeshaft, R., 1973-1981 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Shakeshaft, Robin; J. M. Feagin and L. Kocbach, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Figure from Shakeshaft article, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Smirnov, B. M., 1969 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Sokolov, Igor, Bryce S. DeWitt, and A Ya Burinskii, 1975, 1988, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Spruch, Grace Marmor, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Starace, Anthony F., 1972 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Steigman, Gary, 1969-1978 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Steigman, Gary, 1988-1996 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Sucher, Joe, 1966-1986 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Sucher, J., 1985 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Sucher, Joe, 1989-1999 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Sucher, J., 1996-1998, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Sucher, J., undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Suydam, Bergen R., 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Swan, P., 1953 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Szalewicz, Krzysztof, 1994-1996 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Takayanagi, Kazuo, 1966-1976 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Thirring, W. E., 1978-1990 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Thirring, Walter, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Thomas, L. H., 1927 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Thorne, Kip S., 1969 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Toennies, Peter J., 1994 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Tomishima, Yasuo, Kazuhiro Matsuno, and Katsumi Yonei, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 47)